{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Spice Islands","incorrectAnswers":["The Coral Islands","The Hidden Islands","The Sunken Islands"],"question":"What was the former name of the Moluccas, islands known for cloves, mace, and nutmeg?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pulp Fiction","incorrectAnswers":["Saving Private Ryan","The Treasure of the Sierra Madre","Memento"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The lives of mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster and his wife, and a pair of bandits intertwine in four tales.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Pretenders","incorrectAnswers":["The Pogues","Def Leppard","Journey"],"question":"Chrissie Hynde was in which early eighties group?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Era of Good Feeling","incorrectAnswers":["Age of Enlightenment","Antebellum Period","Jacksonian Era"],"question":"What term is often closely associated with James Monroe's presidency?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ka","incorrectAnswers":["Ki","Hai","Ko"],"question":"In Egyptian mythology, what is the life force called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Funambulist","incorrectAnswers":["Gubbins","Kerfuffle","Hullaballoo"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a tightrope walker'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Basket Case\" by Green Day","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","\"American Pie\" by Don McLean","\"Gangsta's Paradise\" by Coolio feat. L.V."],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Do you have the time to listen to me whine...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which band was Charlie Watts a member of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Stendhal","Paulo Coelho","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Candide'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lithosphere","incorrectAnswers":["Troposphere","Dentosphere","Dirtosphere"],"question":"What is the name given to Earth's outer layer of surface soil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rosh Hashanah","incorrectAnswers":["Yom Kippur","Hanukkah","Passover"],"question":"Which of these holidays is celebrates the Jewish New Year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Little Dorrit'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mirrors","incorrectAnswers":["Bones","Crystals","Wood"],"question":"What substance was traditionally thought to damage one's soul when broken because vampires have no soul? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Stork","incorrectAnswers":["Pelican","Crane","Swallow"],"question":"Which bird is associated with delivering babies?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aerosmith","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Music from Another Dimension!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"PVC","incorrectAnswers":["Plastic","Nylon","PoVy"],"question":"Developed in the USA in 1930, by what name is poly vinyl chloride better known?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neil Gaiman","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","H. P. Lovecraft","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Sandman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Dead Souls'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mozzarella","incorrectAnswers":["Gouda","Blue Cheese","Feta"],"question":"What type of cheese is used on a pizza?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dollar","incorrectAnswers":["Pound","Rino","Sing"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for Singapore?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Bahrain is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jeremy Renner","incorrectAnswers":["Don Cheadle","Benedict Wong","Chris Hemsworth"],"question":"Who plays the role of Hawkeye in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gorbachev","incorrectAnswers":["Yeltsin","Stalin","Khrushchev"],"question":"Who became General Secretary of the Soviet Communist Party in March 1985, and would go on to make significant changes to the country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Laos is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ultra Heat Treated ","incorrectAnswers":["Unbonded Holisticly Treated","Unified Head Treatment","Unilateral Heavy Tarry"],"question":"What Do The Initials U.H.T Refer To In Relation To Milk","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1975","incorrectAnswers":["1965","1970","1980"],"question":"In which year was Monty Python and the Holy Grail first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Eleven","incorrectAnswers":["Fourteen","Thirteen","Twelve"],"question":"How many players make up a field hockey team?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"La Vie En Rose","incorrectAnswers":["Girls Just Want to Have Fun","I Will Always Love You","Borderline"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Édith Piaf, was later covered by Grace Jones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Universe","incorrectAnswers":["The Milky Way","Andromeda","Infinity"],"question":"What was created with the big bang?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mr. T","incorrectAnswers":["Carl Weathers","Hulk Hogan","Dolph Lundgren"],"question":"Which actor played the character Clubber Lang, the rival of Sylvester Stallone's character in Rocky III?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Hoops","incorrectAnswers":["The Terriers","The Gunners","The Canaries"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Queens Park Rangers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kajagoogoo","incorrectAnswers":["Norman Greenbaum","Suzi Quatro","The Vapors"],"question":"'Too Shy' was a one hit wonder in 1983 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Final Problem'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"You turned to stone","incorrectAnswers":["You fell in love","You became a ghost","You saw your own death"],"question":"What Happened If You Looked A Gorgon In The Eye?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mandolin","incorrectAnswers":["French Horn","Bugle","Cowbell"],"question":"Which of these is a stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Belarus"],"question":"In which country is the city of Kharkiv?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Ribbon pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is penne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Trouble","incorrectAnswers":["Life","Risk","Checkers"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must be the first to send all four of their pieces all the way round a board?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Jenny","A Worker","A Lioness"],"question":"What is the word for a female seal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Sound and the Fury","incorrectAnswers":["Lolita","Wise Blood","Master and Commander"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Benjy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which British musician, actor, record producer and arranger released the album 'The Man Who Sold the World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Guaro","incorrectAnswers":["Unicum","Sang Som Rum","Sangria"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Costa Rica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Arc de Triomphe","incorrectAnswers":["Le Louvre","The Eiffel Tower","Notre Dame Cathedral"],"question":"What did Napoleon have built to commemorate his victories?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1990","1998"],"question":"The Shawshank Redemption was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"New Edition","incorrectAnswers":["Shinedown","Fleetwood Mac","The Rooftop Singers "],"question":"With Which Teen Band Did Bobby Brown Sing With Before Going Solo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1066","incorrectAnswers":["1166","1266","1366"],"question":"In Which Year Did The Battle Of Hastings Take Place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","The Hobbit","Taras Bulba"],"question":"In which book does the White Rabbit appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Evander Holyfield","incorrectAnswers":["Mike Tyson","Oscar De La Hoya","Floyd Mayweather"],"question":"Which Heavweight Boxer Was Known As The Real Deal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ivory Coast","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Togo","Benin"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oklahoma","incorrectAnswers":["Texas","California","New York"],"question":"Which is the only US state whose official song was written for a Broadway musical?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oxford","incorrectAnswers":["Manchester","London","York"],"question":"In which English city did Roger Bannister become the first man to run a mile in under 4 minutes? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Humans","incorrectAnswers":["Disease","Insects","The origins of words"],"question":"What is Anthropology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Guatemala","Jamaica"],"question":"What did British Honduras change its name to in 1973?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which musician released the song 'Let's Dance'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Poisons","incorrectAnswers":["Radiation","Abstract Categorisation","Venomous Animals"],"question":"What Is Toxicology The Study Of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Stendhal","Paulo Coelho","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Complete Works of Voltaire'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Intel","incorrectAnswers":["IBM","Microsoft","Apple"],"question":"Which  company did Hungarian-born Andrew Grove transform into the world's largest semiconductor manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Ugly Duckling'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X-Men: Days of Future Past?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jeff Bezos","incorrectAnswers":["Elon Musk","Bill Gates","Mark Zuckerberg"],"question":"Who is the founder of Amazon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Ireland","United Kingdom","Australia"],"question":"In which country is the city of Queenstown?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Solomon","incorrectAnswers":["Balthazar","Melchior","Caspar"],"question":"Which of the following was NOT one of the Three Kings in the nativity?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Camera obscura","incorrectAnswers":["Box camera","Bridge camera","Periscope"],"question":"What simple type of \"camera\" uses a hole in a screen to create a simply-viewed image of the sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bagpipe","incorrectAnswers":["Trumpted","Maraca","Fiddle"],"question":"Which of these is a woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Elective monarchy","incorrectAnswers":["Absolute monarchy","Republic","Constitutional monarchy"],"question":"What type of government did the Holy Roman Empire have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Best Shot","incorrectAnswers":["Rhythm Stick","Lovin'","Poison Arrow"],"question":"Pat Benatar Asked You To \"Hit Me With Your ________\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["Spice Girls","Blondie","Alice in Chains"],"question":"Which band was Stevie Nicks a member of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The life of the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule.","incorrectAnswers":["A free black man from upstate New York is abducted and sold.","A skilled forger and conman is pursued by an FBI agent.","Two grifters team up to pull off the ultimate con."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Gandhi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Ecuador","France"],"question":"Poutine is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Florida ","incorrectAnswers":["South America","France","Mexico"],"question":"Where Does Key Lime Pie Come From?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicolas Cage","incorrectAnswers":["Will Smith","Robert Downey Jr.","Morgan Freeman"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Leaving Las Vegas and Kick-Ass?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Brahman","incorrectAnswers":["Veda","Buddha","Vishnu"],"question":"What is the name given to the supreme reality in Hinduism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Scotland","Cameroon","Mauritius"],"question":"Tandoori Chicken is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Seventeen Seconds'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Genius of Love","incorrectAnswers":["Maniac","Heart And Soul","Lovin' You"],"question":"What song did Tom Tom Club have a hit with in 1982?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jin Yong","incorrectAnswers":["C. S. Lewis","Edgar Rice Burroughs","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Return of the Condor Heroes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"In My Opinion ","incorrectAnswers":["Internet Moderator Organisation","Interesting Mention Of","I Might Object"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'IMO' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Glenn Close","incorrectAnswers":["Olivia Newton-John","Judy Garland","Anne Bancroft"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Alex Forrest in Fatal Attraction?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jordan","incorrectAnswers":["Bosnia and Herzegovina","Lesotho","Uganda"],"question":"Amman is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Sopranos","incorrectAnswers":["Breaking Bad","The Wire","The Godfather"],"question":"Which TV show, known for its portrayal of the Italian-American mafia, features a character named Ralphie Cifaretto?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iceland","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Russia","Greece"],"question":"In 2010, air traffic across Europe was disrupted by the Eyjafjallajokull volcano in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"1.5kg","incorrectAnswers":["500g","1kg","2kg"],"question":"To The Nearest 250 Grams What Is The Average Weight Of An Adult Brain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Friends","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld","The Simpsons","Frasier"],"question":"Which popular '90s show featured the character of Ross Geller?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Blueberry","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Kiwi","Pineapple"],"question":"Which of these fruits is native to North America?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hanoi","incorrectAnswers":["Ho Chi Minh City","Da Nang","Hue"],"question":"In which Vietnamese city are Ho Chi Minh's remains displayed in a mausoleum in Ba Dinh Square?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Timothy Dalton","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Roger Moore","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The Living Daylights?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Political philosopher who promoted a theory of liberal democracy and a social contract.","incorrectAnswers":["Renaissance sculptor, painter and architect","Explorer who landed in America.","Biologist who discovered penicillin."],"question":"Which of the following describes John Locke?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hydra","incorrectAnswers":["Hades","Chimera","Harpies"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who had many heads?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the song 'Enter Sandman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Pigeonhole","incorrectAnswers":["Dovetail","Crowstuff","Owlnook"],"question":"Which term meaning \"to rigidly categorize\" comes from small desk compartments?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stamen","incorrectAnswers":["Style","Stigma","Filament"],"question":"What Is The Male Part Of A Flower Called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["Two","One","Six"],"question":"How many seams are there on an American football?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","South Africa","Algeria"],"question":"Urdu is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Maggot","incorrectAnswers":["An Owlet","A Hatchling","A Caterpillar"],"question":"What is the word for a young fly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carroll","incorrectAnswers":["Enid Blyton","George Orwell","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Jabberwocky'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Melbourne","incorrectAnswers":["Queenstown","Auckland","Wellington"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Australia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["String","Wind","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a glockenspiel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Solomon Islands","incorrectAnswers":["Burkina Faso","Panama","Brunei"],"question":"Honiara is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"El Greco","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","Michelangelo","Raphael"],"question":"Which artist painted \"View of Toledo\"","difficulty":"hard"},